Guide to the Class of 1956, Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Class of 1956, Yale College, records
1981-1981
RU 1123
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(7 boxes)
This collecion consists of six reel-to-reel audio tape recordings with accompanying transcripts of lectures and panel discussions from the Class of 1956 twenty-fifth reunion, held in May 1981. The recordings were created by the Yale Association, the predecessor to the Association of Yale Alumni.
Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1956
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of six reel-to-reel audio tape recordings with accompanying transcripts of lectures and panel discussions from the Class of 1956 twenty-fifth reunion, held in May 1981. The recordings were created by the Yale Association, the predecessor to the Association of Yale Alumni.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
Arranged as received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William H.H. Rees, 2012.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 10-A (YRG 10-A), Records of Yale College classes.
Class reunions; Audiotapes; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1956; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Twenty-fifth Reunion events, Accession 2013-A-041
  - Class of 1956 dinner at Yale University Commons, 1981 May 30
    General
    Speakers are Class Secretary Martin Bowen and Yale University President A. Bartlett Giamatti.
    - Recording, 1 (Box 1)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Dinner program is also included.
  - Lecture by Ivan Selin, "Primer for the Great Defense Debate of the '80s", 1981 May 30
    - Recording, 1 (Box 2)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lecture by Dr. Caldwell Esselstyn, "Primary Operable Breast Cancer -- Alternatives to Mastectomy", 1981 May 30
    - Recording, 1 (Box 3)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Panel discussion, "Career Options", 1981 May 30
    Partcipants are Lisa Barlow, Yale 1981 (moderator); Peter Hutt, Esquire; Marshall Kaplan, MD; and John Hesse, MBA. Discussion was held at Sheffield-Sterling-Strathcona Hall.
    - Recording, 1 (Box 4)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Panel discussion, "The Things That Make Life Worth Living", 1981 May 29
    Participants were Benson Scotch (moderator), John FitzGibbon, Mrs. Peter Tomei (Cleo Whitten), Peter B. F. Randolph, and Jocke S. Stevenson. Discussion was held at Woolsey Hall.
    - Recording, 1 (Box 5)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Panel discussion, "The Wives of the Class of 1956", 1981 May 30
    Participants were Mrs. Thomas (Mary Lee) Jamieson (moderator), Linda Braun, Leanna Y. Brown, Clare Crawford-Mason, Georgia P. Foster, and Peggy G. Kingsbury. Discussion was held at Sprague Hall.
    - Recording, 1 (Box 6)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 6)